Guide to the Mary Vareen scrapbook, Circa 1928-1930 MVC0063.MS
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Mary Vareen scrapbook
circa 1928-1930
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
MVC0063.MS
2 Linear Feet 2 flat boxes
This collection contains the personal scrapbook of Mary Vareen, student at Mount Vernon Seminary circa 1928-1930. The contents include personal correspondence with family and friends (including telegrams and letters), photographs, programs from social events, newpaper clippings, and school-related materials.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
Arranged in the scrapbook's original order with any loose items placed at the end.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. Richard E. Coen, September 7, 2011 (2011.062)
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the scrapbook of Mary Vareen, which includes photographs, personal correspondence, programs from concerts and other social events, postcards, small crafts, school-related papers, newspaper clippings, and other ephemera. The materials range in date from circa 1928-1930.
Biographical / Historical
Mary Vareen was a student at Mount Vernon Seminary circa 1928-1930. The Mount Vernon Seminary began in 1875 as a private high school and junior college for women, founded by Elizabeth J. Somers. The George Washington University initially affiliated with Mount Vernon College, and ultimately acquired the college's property and legacy in 1999.
Mary Vareen attended Mount Vernon Seminary while it was located at the Nebraska Avenue campus.
Women -- Education; Scrapbooks; Women's colleges; Mount Vernon Seminary
- Front cover, circa 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Pages 1-6, circa 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Pages 7-12, circa 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Pages 13-14, circa 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Page 15, circa 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Page 16, circa 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Page 17, circa 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Page 18, circa 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Page 19, circa 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Pages 20-21, circa 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Pages 22-23, circa 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Page 24, circa 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Page 25, circa 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Page 26, circa 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Page 27, circa 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Page 28, circa 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Page 29, circa 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Page 30, circa 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Page 31, circa 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Page 32, circa 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Page 33, circa 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Page 34, circa 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Pages 35-39, circa 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Page 40, circa 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Page 41, circa 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Pages 42-43, circa 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Page 44, circa 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Page 45, circa 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Page 46, circa 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Page 47, circa 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Page 48, circa 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Page 49, circa 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Page 50, circa 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Page 51, circa 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Loose items, circa 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Loose photos, circa 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Loose items, circa 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Loose post cards, circa 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Loose items, circa 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Loose items, circa 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Loose items, circa 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Back cover, circa 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 23)